{
  "name" : "DSA quiz 2",
  "totalQue": 10,
  "questions" : [
    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "Which of these best describes an array?",
      "options" : [
        "A data structure that shows a hierarchical behavior",
        "Container of objects of similar types",
        "Arrays are immutable once initialised",
        "Array is not a data structure"
      ],
      "correct" : ["Container of objects of similar types"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "When does the ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException occur?",
      "options" : [
        "Compile-time",
        "Run-time",
        "Not an error",
        "Not an exception at all"
      ],
      "correct" : ["Run-time"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "Elements in an array are accessed _____________",
      "options" : [
        "randomly",
        "sequentially",
        "exponentially",
        "logarithmically"
      ],
      "correct" : ["randomly"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "In a stack, if a user tries to remove an element from an empty stack it is called _________",
      "options" : [
        "Underflow",
        "Empty collection",
        "Overflow",
        "Garbage Collection"
      ],
      "correct" : ["Underflow"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "Which data structure is used for implementing recursion?",
      "options" : [
        "Queue",
        "Stack",
        "Array",
        "List"
      ],
      "correct" : ["Stack"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 3,
      "question" : "When an array is passed to a function, the function receives a copy of the array (call by value)",
      "options" : [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct" : ["False"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 3,
      "question" : "An O(log N) algorithm is slower than an O(N) algorithm",
      "options" : [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correct" : ["False"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "With what data structure can a priority queue be implemented?",
      "options" : [
        "Array",
        "List",
        "Heap",
        "Tree"
      ],
      "correct" : ["Tree"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "Which of the following is not an application of priority queue?",
      "options" : [
        "Huffman codes",
        "Interrupt handling in operating system",
        "Undo operation in text editors",
        "Bayesian spam filter"
      ],
      "correct" : ["Undo operation in text editors"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    },

    {
      "type" : 1,
      "question" : "What is the worst case time complexity of inserting a node in a doubly linked list?",
      "options" : [
        "O(nlogn)",
        "O(logn)",
        "O(n)",
        "O(1)"
      ],
      "correct" : ["O(n)"],
      "topic" : ["OS"],
      "lastSolved" : false
    }
  ],
  "time" : "10",
  "isSolved" : false
}
